Guide to the Cornell University Department of Psychology Candid Camera Collection, 1961-1966
Cornell University Department of Psychology Candid Camera Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Department of Psychology Candid Camera Collection, 1961-1966
14-23-4224
Cornell University. Department of Psychology.
5 cubic feet
16mm film.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Copies of films from the Candid Camera television series showing various practical jokes on the unsuspecting public. The films were used by the Psychology Department in class and for research to document human behavior. Included are a more than 200 episodes dated throughout 1961 and 1966. Professor James Maas used the films in his Psychology 101 class until his retirement in 2011.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Candid Camera was a practical joke reality television show produced by Allen Funt, who received a BA in Fine Arts from Cornell University in 1934.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Copies of films from the Candid Camera television series showing various practical jokes on the unsuspecting public. The films were used by the Psychology Department in class and for research to document human behavior. Included are a more than 200 episodes dated throughout 1961 and 1966. Professor James Maas used the films in his Psychology 101 class until his retirement in 2011. Several canisters did not contain the episodes they were labeled to, including Rude Waiter (10/27/1963), Disquis Throws, Surprise TV Commercial (3/15/1964), Kids With Box ( 10/21/62), Kids Make Up (2/4/62), Piano School, and California Dogs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University. Department of Psychology.
Titles:
Candid camera (Television program).
Subjects:
Psychologists.
Form and Genre Terms:
16mm
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Paulwinchell Motel, 10/1/1961; F-1316 (Box 1)
- Two Phone, 10/1/1961; F-1317 (Box 1)
- Note on Windshield, 10/1/1961; F-1318 (Box 1)
- Diving, 10/1/1961; F-1319 (Box 1)
- Russian Show Parts 1-3 (Oversized), 10/15/1961; F-1320-F-1322 (Box 10)
- Kirby Bomb, 11/12/1961; F-1323 (Box 1)
- 3-A, 11/12/1961; F-1324 (Box 1)
- Falling Boxes, 11/12/1961; F-1325 (Box 1)
- No Hole Golf, 11/12/1961; F-1326 (Box 1)
- Coast Guard, 11/26/1961; F-1327 (Box 1)
- Joelson Sings, 11/26/1961; F-1328 (Box 1)
- Record Cleaners, 11/26/1961; F-1329 (Box 1)
- Naptime, 12/10/1961; F-1330 (Box 1)
- Alphonse and Gastone, 12/10/1961; F-1331 (Box 1)
- Choir, 12/10/1961; F-1332 (Box 1)
- Flattery, 12/10/1961; F-1333 (Box 1)
- Rowboats, 12/10/1961; F-1334 (Box 1)
- Canada Cigar - Dinner Kiss, 12/24/1961; F-1335 (Box 1)
- Mannequin, 12/24/1961; F-1336 (Box 1)
- Crime and Punishment (Oversized), 1/12/1962; F-1337 (Box 9)
- Black and White Squares, 1/14/1962; F-1338 (Box 1)
- Musical Comedy, 1/14/1962; F-1339 (Box 1)
- Silhouette, 1/14/1962; F-1340 (Box 1)
- Washing Faces, 1/14/1962; F-1341 (Box 1)
- Cream, 1/21/1962; F-1342 (Box 1)
- Hand Reaching, 1/21/1962; F-1343 (Box 1)
- Cup and Saucer, 1/21/1962; F-1344 (Box 2)
- Stuck Phone, 1/21/1962; F-1345 (Box 2)
- Sue-Sue, 1/21/1962; F-1346 (Box 2)
- Where Is North Pole, 1/21/1962; F-1347 (Box 2)
- Al Kelly, 1/28/1962; F-1348 (Box 2)
- Feet Wiping, 1/28/1962; F-1349 (Box 2)
- Jimmy Dean (Oversized), 1/28/1962; F-1350 (Box 9)
- Thermometer, 1/28/1962; F-1351 (Box 2)
- Fruit Stand, 2/4/1962; F-1352 (Box 2)
- Vivian Vance, 2/4/1962; F-1353 (Box 2)
- Yoyo, 2/4/1962; F-1354 (Box 2)
- Egg Breaking, 2/11/1962; F-1355 (Box 2)
- Shopping Bags, 2/11/1962; F-1356 (Box 2)
- Bits and Pieces, 3/4/1962; F-1357 (Box 2)
- Flying Phone, 3/4/1962; F-1358 (Box 2)
- Air Hammer, 9/30/1962; F-1359 (Box 2)
- Diaper Sextet, 9/30/1962; F-1360 (Box 2)
- Saroyan (Oversized), 9/30/1962; F-1361 (Box 9)
- Stuck Horn, 10/21/1962; F-1362 (Box 2)
- Wrong Floor, 10/21/1962; F-1363 (Box 2)
- Bank Doors, 10/28/1962; F-1364 (Box 2)
- Kangaroo, 10/28/1962; F-1365 (Box 2)
- Lemonade, 10/28/1962; F-1366 (Box 2)
- Mechanical Girl, 10/28/1962; F-1367 (Box 2)
- Apology, 12/23/1962; F-1368 (Box 2)
- Autograph, 12/23/1962; F-1369 (Box 2)
- Christmas Girl, 12/23/1962; F-1370 (Box 3)
- Midget, 12/23/1962; F-1371 (Box 3)
- Nothing Box, 12/23/1962; F-1372 (Box 3)
- Carol Lawrence, 1/6/1963; F-1373 (Box 3)
- Coat Hook, 1/6/1963; F-1374 (Box 3)
- Up a Tree, 1/6/1963; F-1375 (Box 3)
- Foreign Phones, 1/13/1963; F-1376 (Box 3)
- Four Men With Carnation, 1/20/1963; F-1377 (Box 3)
- Finger in Air, 1/20/1963; F-1378 (Box 3)
- Pedestrian Stoplight, 1/20/1963; F-1379 (Box 3)
- Wrong Hat, 1/20/1963; F-1380 (Box 3)
- Baby Pictures, 1/27/1963; F-1381 (Box 3)
- Candid Quickies, 1/27/1963; F-1382 (Box 3)
- Candid Quickies - Ukranians, 1/27/1963; F-1383 (Box 3)
- Gum Chewing, 1/27/1963; F-1384 (Box 3)
- Pillow Fight, 1/27/1963; F-1385 (Box 3)
- Sinking Stool, 1/27/1963; F-1386 (Box 3)
- Jonathan, 5/12/1963; F-1387 (Box 3)
- Quickies, 5/12/1963; F-1388 (Box 3)
- Standing on Foot, 5/12/1963; F-1389 (Box 3)
- Bad Flowers, 5/19/1963; F-1390 (Box 3)
- Eyes, 5/19/1963; F-1391 (Box 3)
- Ladies Baseball, 5/19/1963; F-1392 (Box 3)
- Sinking Chair, 5/19/1963; F-1393 (Box 3)
- Bird Watching, 6/2/1963; F-1394 (Box 4)
- Empty Armour, 6/2/1963; F-1395 (Box 4)
- From an Admirer (Oversized), 6/2/1963; F-1396 (Box 9)
- Growing Flowers, 6/2/1963; F-1397-F-1398 (Box 4)
- Chester Morris plus Quickies (Oversized), 6/9/1963; F-1399 (Box 9)
- Rubber Hot Dogs, 6/2/1963; F-1400 (Box 4)
- English Kisses, 6/9/1963; F-1401 (Box 4)
- Trick Camera, 6/9/1963; F-1402 (Box 4)
- Lyndon Johnson, 9/29/1963; F-1403 (Box 4)
- Kansas Fair, 9/29/1963; F-1404 (Box 4)
- Rhythm, 9/29/1963; F-1405 (Box 4)
- Barber of Seville (Oversized), 9/29/1963; F-1406 (Box 9)
- Jack Paar Cop, 10/13/1963; F-1407 (Box 4)
- Melons, 10/13/1963; F-1408 (Box 4)
- Picketing, 10/13/1963; F-1409 (Box 4)
- Charades, 10/27/1963; F-1410 (Box 4)
- Hot Seat, 10/27/1963; F-1411 (Box 4)
- High School, 11/10/1963; F-1412 (Box 4)
- Marty Engles Cribbing, 11/10/1963; F-1413 (Box 4)
- Reaching for Cake, 11/10/1963; F-1414 (Box 4)
- Triplets, 11/10/1963; F-1415 (Box 4)
- Oscar Brant Parking Meter, 11/17/1963; F-1416 (Box 4)
- Roll Up Paper, 11/17/1963; F-1417 (Box 4)
- Throwing Pies, 11/17/1963; F-1418 (Box 4)
- Beep Phone, 12/15/1963; F-1419 (Box 4)
- Plastic Candy, 12/15/1963; F-1420 (Box 4)
- Two Phones in Booth, 12/15/1963; F-1421 (Box 5)
- Wrong Night Party, 12/15/1963; F-1422 (Box 5)
- Combo 1-3, 1/5/1964; F-1423 (Box 5)
- Lou Laughing, 1/5/1964; F-1456 (Box 5)
- Good Samaritan, 1/12/1964; F-1424 (Box 5)
- Grocery Boy (Oversized), 1/12/1964; F-1425 (Box 10)
- Subway Baby, 1/12/1964; F-1426 (Box 5)
- Topless Counter, 1/12/1964; F-1427 (Box 5)
- Kids Skating (Oversized), 1/12/1964; F-1427b (Box 10)
- $100 Mistake, 1/19/1964; F-1428 (Box 5)
- Combo, 1/19/1964; F-1429 (Box 5)
- Phone Vision (Oversized), 1/19/1964; F-1430 (Box 14)
- Grayline Tour, 1/26/1964; F-1431 (Box 5)
- Do Not Eat Light, 2/9/1964; F-1432 (Box 5)
- Long Handshake, 2/9/1964; F-1433 (Box 5)
- Typewriter, 2/9/1964; F-1434 (Box 5)
- Diplomats, 3/15/1964; F-1435 (Box 5)
- Orange Peeling, 3/15/1964; F-1436 (Box 5)
- Soda Commercial (Oversized), 3/15/1964; F-1437 (Box 14)
- Beatles (Oversized), 3/15/1964; F-1437b (Box 10)
- Booking Office, 3/29/1964; F-1438 (Box 5)
- Coffee Urn, 3/29/1964; F-1439 (Box 5)
- Irresistable Perfume, 3/29/1964; F-1440 (Box 5)
- Cab Driver, 4/12/1964; F-1441 (Box 5)
- Angel and Devil, 4/19/1964; F-1442 (Box 5)
- Atlanta Bank, 4/19/1964; F-1443 (Box 5)
- Atlanta Kids, 4/19/1964; F-1444 (Box 5)
- Bullet Hole, 4/19/1964; F-1445 (Box 5)
- No Hamburger, 4/19/1964; F-1446 (Box 5)
- Combo, 4/26/1964; F-1447 (Box 5)
- East Lynne, 4/26/1964; F-1448 (Box 6)
- Poker Face, 4/26/1964; F-1449 (Box 6)
- Armchair, 5/3/1964; F-1450 (Box 6)
- Combo, 5/3/1964; F-1451 (Box 6)
- Crane Phone Booth, 5/3/1964; F-1452 (Box 6)
- Russell Chamberlain, 5/3/1964; F-1453 (Box 6)
- Two Bosses, 5/3/1964; F-1454 (Box 6)
- Combo, 5/17/1964; F-1455 (Box 6)
- Long White Thread, 5/17/1964; F-1457 (Box 6)
- Lunch Order (Oversized), 5/17/1964; F-1458 (Box 14)
- Peanut Butter and Jelly, 5/17/1964; F-1459 (Box 6)
- Al Kelly Dictation, 5/24/1964; F-1460 (Box 6)
- Disappearing Cigarette, 5/24/1964; F-1461 (Box 6)
- Plumber-Beer, 5/24/1964; F-1462 (Box 6)
- Hot Seat, 5/31/1964; F-1463 (Box 6)
- Nursery in Nashville, 5/31/1964; F-1464 (Box 6)
- Railroad Crossing in Nashville, 5/31/1964; F-1465 (Box 6)
- Surprise Guest in Nashville, 5/31/1964; F-1466 (Box 6)
- Broken Golf Basket, 6/28/1964; F-1467 (Box 6)
- CC Quickies, 6/28/1964; F-1468 (Box 6)
- Debbie - Award, 6/28/1964; F-1469 (Box 6)
- Foodmeter, 6/28/1964; F-1470 (Box 6)
- Smiles -- Reprise, 6/28/1964; F-1471 (Box 6)
- Lady Doctor, 10/26/1964; F-1472 (Box 6)
- Baton Twirling, 1/17/1965; F-1473 (Box 7)
- New Baby, 1/17/1965; F-1474 (Box 7)
- Teleprompter, 1/17/1965; F-1475 (Box 7)
- Wrong Hotel Room, 1/17/1965; F-1476 (Box 7)
- Auction, 3/28/1965; F-1477 (Box 7)
- Candid Camera Quickies, 3/28/1965; F-1478 (Box 7)
- Children in Classroom, 3/28/1965; F-1479 (Box 7)
- Dirty Hands, 3/28/1965; F-1480 (Box 7)
- Walkie Talkie, 3/28/1965; F-1481 (Box 7)
- Echo Quin, 5/9/1965; F-1482 (Box 7)
- Elevator Stairway, 5/9/1965; F-1483 (Box 7)
- Kids Cheerleading (Oversized), 5/9/1965; F-1484 (Box 14)
- Square Yards, 5/9/1965; F-1485 (Box 7)
- The Visit (Oversized), 5/9/1965; F-1486 (Box 14)
- Boston A Go Go, 5/16/1965; F-1487 (Box 7)
- Kids Drummers, 5/16/1965; F-1488 (Box 7)
- Mother's Diner, 5/16/1965; F-1489 (Box 7)
- Older Kids Jokes, 5/16/1965; F-1490 (Box 7)
- Sidewars Cars, 5/16/1965; F-1491 (Box 7)
- Whistling, 5/16/1965; F-1492 (Box 7)
- Sneeze Phone, 5/23/1965; F-1493 (Box 7)
- Who Was That, 5/23/1965; F-1494 (Box 7)
- Worlds Fair Feet, 5/23/1965; F-1495 (Box 7)
- Belly Button, 1/16/1966; F-1496 (Box 7)
- Phone Booth Weather, 1/16/1966; F-1497 (Box 7)
- Greeting Card Lady, 1/16/1966; F-1498 (Box 8)
- Noodlesoup, 1/16/1966; F-1499 (Box 8)
- Pratt Fall, 1/16/1966; F-1500 (Box 8)
- Sidewalk Rug, 1/16/1966; F-1501 (Box 8)
- Bon Voyage Party, 5/29/1966; F-1502 (Box 8)
- Hand Wrestling, 5/29/1966; F-1503 (Box 8)
- Impatient Child, 5/29/1966; F-1504 (Box 8)
- Hugs and Kisses, 5/29/1966; F-1505 (Box 8)
- Kids Intercom Part 1, 5/29/1966; F-1506 (Box 8)
- Kids Intercom Part 2, 5/29/1966; F-1507 (Box 8)
- Kids Tap Dance, 5/29/1966; F-1508 (Box 8)
- Silent Band, 5/29/1966; F-1509 (Box 8)
- Emmy Awards and Smiles, 6/5/1966; F-1510 (Box 8)
- Kids Mystery Package, 6/5/1966; F-1511 (Box 8)
- Save My Seat, 6/5/1966; F-1512 (Box 8)
- Falling Door, 9/11/1966; F-1513 (Box 8)
- No Bathroom, 9/11/1966; F-1514 (Box 8)
- Who Do You Look Like, 9/11/1966; F-1515 (Box 8)
- Roman Forum (Oversized), 9/11/1966; F-1516 (Box 14)
- Bakery Name Dropping, 9/18/1966; F-1517 (Box 8)
- Bess Myerson, 9/18/1966; F-1518 (Box 8)
- Falstsaff Award, 9/18/1966; F-1519 (Box 8)
- Statue of Liberty, 9/18/1966; F-1520 (Box 8)
- Breaking Pencils, 9/19/1966; F-1521 (Box 8)
- Discotheque, 9/19/1966; F-1522 (Box 8)
- Earth Began, 9/19/1966; F-1523 (Box 9)
- Jackie Mason, 9/19/1966; F-1524 (Box 9)
- Ohio Cop, 9/19/1966; F-1525 (Box 9)
- Five Dollar Friend, 10/2/1966; F-1526 (Box 9)
- Old Folks Fashion, 10/2/1966; F-1527 (Box 9)
- Hula Hoop, 10/2/1966; F-1528 (Box 9)
- Job Intercom, 10/2/1966; F-1529 (Box 9)
- Carpenters Paradise, 10/9/1966; F-1530 (Box 9)
- Kindergarten, 10/9/1966; F-1531 (Box 9)
- Small Steak, 10/9/1966; F-1532 (Box 9)
- Teen Age John Alden, 10/9/1966; F-1533 (Box 9)
- Insurance Sleeping, 10/13/1966; F-1534 (Box 9)
- Mice In Earrings, 10/13/1966; F-1535 (Box 10)
- Myerson Kitchen, 10/13/1966; F-1536 (Box 10)
- Who Do You Look Like, 10/13/1966; F-1537 (Box 10)
- Allen English Kids, 10/23/1966; F-1538 (Box 10)
- Combo, 10/23/1966; F-1539 (Box 10)
- Horse Race Tips, 10/23/1966; F-1540 (Box 10)
- Kilts (Oversized), 10/23/1966; F-1541 (Box 14)
- Automatic Picture Machine, 10/27/1966; F-1542 (Box 10)
- Baby Bottles, 10/30/1966; F-1543 (Box 10)
- Kids Pets Tulsa, 10/30/1966; F-1544 (Box 10)
- Kids Sweaters, 10/30/1966; F-1545 (Box 10)
- Sweet Adelines, 10/30/1966; F-1546 (Box 10)
- Cigar Testimonial, 11/6/1966; F-1547 (Box 10)
- No Exit, 11/6/1966; F-1548 (Box 10)
- Smashing Hood, 11/6/1966; F-1549 (Box 11)
- Spell W, 11/6/1966; F-1550 (Box 11)
- George Kirby (Oversized), 11/6/1966; F-1551 (Box 11)
- Diaper Dolls, 11/7/1966; F-1552 (Box 11)
- Dogs Watch TV, 11/7/1966; F-1553 (Box 11)
- False Eye Lashes, 11/7/1966; F-1554 (Box 11)
- Foot Compliments, 11/7/1966; F-1555 (Box 11)
- No Slot Mailbox, 11/7/1966; F-1556 (Box 11)
- Welcome Manager, 11/7/1966; F-1557 (Box 11)
- Bottle On Head, 12/4/1966; F-1558 (Box 11)
- Keep Busy, 12/4/1966; F-1559 (Box 11)
- Moving Wallpaper, 12/4/1966; F-1560 (Box 11)
- School Lunches, 12/4/1966; F-1561 (Box 11)
- ADS In, Undated; F-1562 (Box 12)
- The Atlanta Celebrity, Undated; F-1563 (Box 12)
- Betsy Palmer / Medic, Undated; F-1564 (Box 12)
- Bosses Awards, Undated; F-1565 (Box 12)
- Boys Long Hair, Undated; F-1566 (Box 12)
- Divided Car, Undated; F-1567 (Box 12)
- Dog Knights, Undated; F-1568 (Box 12)
- Dog's Tails - Heads, Undated; F-1569 (Box 12)
- Dogs Watch TV - Tests, Undated; F-1570 (Box 12)
- Don't Look Up - Chained Car, Undated; F-1571 (Box 12)
- Face The Rear (Silent) #50, Undated; F-1572 (Box 12)
- Give Me a Kiss, Undated; F-1573 (Box 12)
- Glickman Baseball, Undated; F-1574 (Box 13)
- Grapefruit, Undated; F-1575 (Box 13)
- My Country Tiss of Thee, Undated; F-1576 (Box 13)
- Public Steno, Undated; F-1577 (Box 13)
- Scratched Ads, Undated; F-1578 (Box 13)
- Teachers' Descriptions, Undated; F-1579 (Box 13)
- Awards (Oversized), Undated; F-1580 (Box 11)
- Baby Pictures (Oversized), Undated; F-1581 (Box 11)
- Baby Pictures (Oversized), Undated; F-1582 (Box 11)
- Baseball TV (Oversized), Undated; F-1583 (Box 11)
- Bearded Lady (Oversized), Undated; F-1584 (Box 11)
- Breakaway Car (Oversized), Undated; F-1585 (Box 11)
- Breakaway Car (Oversized), Undated; F-1586 (Box 11)
- Black Squares (Silent) (Oversized), Undated; F-1587 (Box 12)
- Candid Camera Titles (Oversized), Undated; F-1588 (Box 12)
- Congressman (Oversized), Undated; F-1589 (Box 14)
- Delaware Close (Oversized), Undated; F-1590 (Box 12)
- Don't Eat Light (Oversized), Undated; F-1591 (Box 12)
- Don't Eat Light (Oversized), Undated; F-1592 (Box 12)
- Drama Minor (Oversized), Undated; F-1593 (Box 14)
- Face The Rear (Oversized), Undated; F-1594 (Box 12)
- Face The Rear (Oversized), Undated; F-1595 (Box 12)
- Face The Rear (Silent) #50 (Oversized), Undated; F-1596 (Box 12)
- Face The Rear (Silent) #50 (Oversized), Undated; F-1597 (Box 13)
- Handsome Teacher (Oversized), Undated; F-1598 (Box 13)
- Handsome Teacher (Oversized), Undated; F-1599 (Box 13)
- Handsome Teacher (Oversized), Undated; F-1600 (Box 13)
- Husband on Leash (Oversized), Undated; F-1601 (Box 13)
- Insurance Salesman (Oversized), Undated; F-1602 (Box 13)
- Kids Eating Ice Cream (Oversized), Undated; F-1603 (Box 14)
- Men's Room, Loveletter, Shoe Store, Ughly Baby Pix, "Sh!" (Oversized), Undated; F-1604 (Box 14)
- Ohio Traffic Cop, Pittsburgh Cop (Oversized), Undated; F-1605 (Box 14)
- Piano School (Oversized), Undated; F-1606 (Box 14)
- Pretty Teacher (Oversized), Undated; F-1607 (Box 14)
- Pretty Teacher (Oversized), Undated; F-1608 (Box 14)
- Public Steno, Awards (Oversized), Undated; F-1609 (Box 14)
- Public Steno, Awards (Oversized), Undated; F-1610 (Box 14)
- Public Steno, Awards, Loveletter (Oversized), Undated; F-1611 (Box 14)
- Restroom (Oversized), Undated; F-1612 (Box 14)
- Sideline (Oversized), Undated; F-1613 (Box 14)
- Squares (Oversized), Undated; F-1614 (Box 14)
- Surprise Test #103 (Oversized), Undated; F-1615 (Box 14)
- Teacher Description (Oversized), Undated; F-1616 (Box 14)
- The Third Eye (Oversized), Undated; F-1617 (Box 14)
- Washing Faces (Oversized), Undated; F-1618 (Box 14)
- Unlabeled (Oversized), Undated; F-1619 (Box 14)
- Candid Camera (Oversized), Undated; F-1620 (Box 14)